Guide to the Homer Jones Papers, 1928-1986
Homer Jones papers 1928-1986
Jones, Homer
600 Items 1.5 Linear Feet
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Durham, North Carolina 27708-0185
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical Note
Homer Jones is an economist.
Collection Overview
Chiefly professional papers of Jones, but also includes some materials of his wife Alice Hanson Jones, and University of Iowa professor Frank Hyneman Knight, relating to their careers as economists. Includes correspondence, printed material, and writings and speeches that relate to Jones's advocacy of monetarist economic theory, the Korean economy, and work for the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis and the Shadow Open Market Committee.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis
Monetary reformers -- Missouri
Korea -- Economic conditions
Jones, Alice Hanson, 1904-1985
Knight, Frank Hyneman, 1885-
Shadow Open Market Committee (U.S.)
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence
  - 1962-1969, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Complimentary letters, 1964-1971
  - Congratulatory letters, promotion to Senior Vice-President. Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis, 1967-1969
  - Knight, Frank H., office correspondence
- Printed Material
  - Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis, Eighth Annual Economic Policy Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Knight, Frank H., articles, 1924-1934, undated, (2 folders)
  - Knight, Frank H., Economics 201-304, lecture, notes, 1929-1934, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Shadow Open Market Committee, 1981-1982
- Writings and Speeches
  - Dissertation, Facilitating the Flow of Saving into Private Investment, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Homer, writings, resumes 1933-1969, (2 folders)
  - Shadow Open Market Committee, notes, 1979-1980, undated
  - Shadow Open Market Committee, writings, 1980
- Miscellaneous
  - 1962-1984, undated (Box 3)